Curt Stern Papers 1907-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
Curt Stern Papers
1907-1981
Mss.Ms.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
21.0 Linear feet
The Papers of Curt Stern include extensive correspondence, lectures (1920s-1970s, 1.5 boxes), autobiographical material, articles, zoological course notes, photographs, etc. Stern's various areas of scientific interest are documented in the collection: the chromosome theory of heredity, role of gene mutation and chromosome rearrangements in evolution, action and interaction of genes during individual development, and particularly his contribution to the development of human genetics as a discipline (centered on his popular and influential book, Principles of Human Genetics, 1949, 1960, 1973). Both his career in Germany and the United States is documented in his correspondence. After studying with T. H. Morgan at Columbia University on a Rockefeller Foundation Fellowship (1924-1926), Stern returned to Richard Goldschmidt's lab at the Kaiser-Wilhelm Institute (1926-1932). There is material of note in the collection concerning this period when Stern helped to establish the cytological basis of crossing over. After a short stay at the California Institute of Technology in 1932, Stern's temporary residence in the U. S. became permanent, and his later career at the University of Rochester, 1933-1947 (Chairman, Department of Zoology) and at the University of California, Berkeley, 1947-1970 (there is abundant material on the Department of Zoology) is covered in the collection. There is other material on: American Association for the Advancement of Science Inter-Society Committee on Science Foundation Legislation, 1946-1947; American Society of Human Genetics (Pres., 1957); Atomic Energy Commission (Advisory Committee for Biology and Medicine, 1950-1955); Genetics (journal); Oak Ridge National Laboratory (Advisory Committee for Biology, 1955-1968); and the Rockefeller Foundation. Stern's correspondence with friends and colleagues in Germany, England, and the U. S., during the 1920s-1930s, is of particular note as it documents not only the developments in genetics and the institutional and administrative networks supporting research, but it also offers general comments and observations on science, Germany, and politics. The photographs (2 boxes) include pictures of many prominent geneticists and scientists.
Stern, Curt, 1902-1981
Bibliography
Bentley Glass, A Guide to the Genetics Collections of the American Philosophical Society (Philadelphia, 1988).
African American History Note
Included in the collection are various materials reflecting Stern's thoughts regarding race: from articles and lectures ( "Biology of the Negro," "General talk on race," "Why do people differ?," "Model estimates of the frequency of white and near white segregants in the American Negro"), to subject files ( Race and racial prejudice, Race crossing in paradise?, UNESCO - statement on race and racial prejudice), and correspondence ( T. Edward Reed and William Shockley, for example).
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Alava, Aloha Margaret Hannah Correspondence (30 items) 1950-1973
American Association for the Advancement of Science. Inter-Society Committee on Science Foundation Legislation Correspondence (3 folders) 1947
Atomic Energy Commission Records (21 items) 1950-1968
American Philosophical Society Correspondence (18 items) 1944-1976
American Society of Human Genetics Records (7 folders) 1954-1975
American Society of Human Genetics. Allen Award Correspondence (17 items) 1962
Astaurov, Boris L. Correspondence (15 items) 1968-1974
Baltzer, Fritz Correspondence (17 items) 1938-1964
Baur, Erwin Correspondence (6 items) 1930-1933
Beadle, George Wells Correspondence (2 folders) 1946-1968
Beadle, Muriel Correspondence (3 items) 1968-1970
Becker, Gweneth Carson Correspondence (9 items) 1960-1969
Becker, Hans Joachim Correspondence (46 items) 1956-1975
Belar, Gertrud Correspondence (11 items) 1929-1956
Belar, Karl Correspondence (36 items) 1925-1931
Bernstein, Felix Correspondence (6 items) 1946-1949
Bernstein, Marianne Wiener Correspondence (23 items) 1949-1970
Bridges, Calvin B. Correspondence (16 items) 1927-1938
Buck, John B. Correspondence (19 items) 1946-1975
California State Department of Education -- The Science of Genetics (Film). Critique Manuscripts (29 pages) 1962-1963
Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm Correspondence (16 items) 1946-1970
Centerwall, Willard R. Correspondence (27 items) 1961-1972
Chicago Cytogenetics Conference Records (4 folders) 1966
Claxton, Jack H. Correspondence (20 items) 1965-1970
Cooper, Kenneth Willard Correspondence (86 items) 1939-1967
de Garay, Alfonso L. Correspondence (28 items) 1967-1973
Delbruck, Max Correspondence (13 items) 1938-1968
Demerec, Milislav Correspondence (140 items) 1933-1947
Dempster, Everett Ross Correspondence (25 items) 1946-1970
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Correspondence (5 folders) 1929-1975
Dronamraju, Krishna R. Correspondence (32 items) 1964-1971
Dunn, Leslie Clarence Correspondence (120 items) 1933-1978
Eakin, Richard M. Correspondence (63 items) 1939-1971
Ephrussi, Boris Correspondence (23 items) 1941-1955
W. H. Freeman and Company W. H. Freeman Foundation Correspondence (66 items) 1949-1972
Frisch, Karl von Correspondence (15 items) 1933-1965
Genetics Correspondence (7 folders) 1940-1967
Genetics Society of America Correspondence (37 items) 1940-1966
Genetics Society of America. Committee on Aid to Geneticists Abroad Correspondence (4 items) 1946-1947
German, James Correspondence (31 items) 1964-1976
Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict Correspondence (88 items) 1921-1957
Gould, Adair Brasted Correspondence (41 items) 1937-1971
Hadorn, Ernst Correspondence (18 items) 1939-1974
Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson Correspondence (31 items) 1929-1965
Hamburger, Viktor Correspondence (29 items) 1927-1969
Hammerling, Joachim Correspondence (35 items) 1929-1980
Hammett, Frederick S. Correspondence (22 items) 1939-1941
Hartmann, Max Correspondence (11 items) 1933-1962
Heidenthal, Gertrude Correspondence (24 items) 1938-1946
Hildreth, Philip Elwin Correspondence (32 items) 1967-1974
Huskins, C. Leonard Correspondence (49 items) 1928-1950
International Congress of Genetics. Twelfth Congress Correspondence (3 folders) 1965-1968
Jeffery, Duane E. Correspondence (24 items) 1969-1975
Kodani, Masuo Correspondence (32 items) 1945-1960
Komai, Taku Correspondence (45 items) 1938-1972
Kuhn, Alfred Correspondence (16 items) 1927-1968
Lederberg, Joshua Correspondence (15 items) 1947-1970
Lewis, Edward B. Correspondence (42 items) 1957-1971
Lucchesi, John C. Correspondence (27 items) 1964-1974
McClintock, Barbara Correspondence (38 items) 1933-1962
McKusick, Victor A. Correspondence (34 items) 1961-1976
Mayr, Ernst Correspondence (46 items) 1943-1974
Mohr, Otto Louis Correspondence (47 items) 1926-1960
Morgan, Thomas Hunt and Morgan, Lilian V. Correspondence (32 items) 1927-1952
Moseley, Helen Rydquest Manuscripts (3 folders) 1943
Mukherjee, Ardendu S. Correspondence (47 items) 1958-1972
Muller, Hermann Joseph Correspondence (198 items) 1926-1972
Nachtsheim, Hans Correspondence (6 items) 1927-1967
National Academy of Sciences Correspondence (39 items) 1948-1978
National Council on Radiation Protection and Measurements Records (6 folders) 1963-1967
Neel, James V. Correspondence (7 folders) 1939-1982
Novitski, Edward Correspondence (5 folders) 1940-1979
Oak Ridge National Laboratory. Advisory Committee for Biology Records (5 folders) 1955-1968
Orel, Vitezslav Correspondence (28 items) 1966-1975
Patterson, John Thomas Correspondence (27 items) 1933-1945
Reed, T. Edward Correspondence (24 items) 1950-1973
Rockefeller Association of Scientists Correspondence (17 items) 1946-1947
Rockefeller Foundation Records (170 items) 1929-1971
Sarkar, S. S. Correspondence (21 items) 1964-1969
Saturday Evening Post -- Adventures of the Mind Correspondence (6 items) 1959-1960
Schaefer, Ann Correspondence (11 items) 1966-1967
Schrader, Franz Correspondence (57 items) 1926-1961
Schrader, Sally Hughes Correspondence (11 items) 1927-1973
Schultz, Jack Correspondence (15 items) 1927-1968
Science Correspondence (27 items) 1937-1972
Scientific Monthly Correspondence (22 items) 1943-1944
Scientists' Committee on Loyalty Problems Records (8 folders) 1946-1950
Seiler, Jakob Correspondence (11 items) 1929-1970
Sekla, Bohumil Correspondence (16 items) 1961-1967
Sherwood, Eva and Stern, Curt Manuscripts (6 folders) 1958-1962, n.d.
Shockley, William Correspondence (8 items) 1965-1973
Shull, George Harrison Correspondence (45 items) 1937-1952
Spencer, Warren P. Correspondence (18 items) 1929-1970
Stadler, Lewis John Correspondence (18 items) 1932-1949
Stern, Curt -- Adventures in Dermatological Genetics Manuscripts (2 folders) 1936-1970
Stern, Curt -- An analysis of crosses involving new allelamorphs of the mutant ebony in Drosophila Manuscripts (1 item) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- The atomic bomb and the scientists Manuscripts (11 pages) 1946
Stern, Curt -- Behavior Genetics Manuscripts (2 folders) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Biographical Information. Biography, "A Geneticist's Journey" Manuscripts (3 folders) 1954-1966
Stern, Curt -- The Biology of the Negro Manuscripts (5 folders) 1954-1956
Stern, Curt -- Calculations, miscellaneous Manuscripts (3 folders) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Congress of Genetics (Thirteenth International, 1973) Manuscripts (2 folders) 1973
Stern, Curt -- Course notes, Biology Manuscripts (10 folders) 1943-1955
Stern, Curt -- Course notes, Zoology Manuscripts (40 folders) 1942-1971
Stern, Curt -- The Cunier pedigree of color blindness Manuscripts (2 folders) 1957-1958
Stern, Curt -- Curriculum Vitae Manuscripts (1 item) 1930
Stern, Curt -- The Cytogenetics of Man Manuscripts (2 items) 1970
Stern, Curt -- Data on [bristles and] sex combs of XY and XO males Manuscripts (7 folders) 1963
Stern, Curt -- Developmental singularities and genetic competence in speciation Manuscripts (6 items) 1957
Stern, Curt -- Diabetes mellitus Manuscripts (1 item) 1959
Stern, Curt -- Die Mitose der Epidermiskerne von Stenostomum Manuscripts (2 items) 1925
Stern, Curt -- Discussion of C. E. McClung, Evolution of Germplasm Manuscripts (1 item) 1940
Stern, Curt -- Down's Syndrome Correspondence (40 items) 1960-1961
Stern, Curt -- Drosophila 2x3A transplantation Manuscripts (1 item) 1968
Stern, Curt -- An effect of temperature and age on crossing over in the first chromosome of Drosophila melanogaster Manuscripts (9 folders) 1926
Stern, Curt -- Evolution of Genetic Systems Manuscripts (1 item) 1959
Stern, Curt -- The gene and how it acts in development Manuscripts (1 folder) 1943
Stern, Curt -- The genetic consequences of radiation Manuscripts (4 pages) 1955
Stern, Curt -- Geneticists (10 most able) Manuscripts (1 item) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Genetics of longevity Manuscripts (3 folders) 1962
Stern, Curt -- The genetics of testicular feminization in male pseudohermaphrodites Manuscripts (1 folder) 1954
Stern, Curt -- R. B. Goldschmidt biographical sketch (notes) Manuscripts Correspondence (9 items) 1958-1963
Stern, Curt -- Honors Manuscripts (37 items) 1958-1964
Stern, Curt -- How a Scientist Develops Manuscripts (1 item) 1956
Stern, Curt -- Human Chromosomes Manuscripts (2 folders) Circa 1958-1959
Stern, Curt -- Human Inheritance Manuscripts (2 folders) 1939
Stern, Curt -- Julian Huxley, Introduction Manuscripts (2 folders) 1950, 1955
Stern, Curt -- Inheritance in the y chromosome of Drosophila Melanogaster Manuscripts (1 folder) 1926
Stern, Curt -- Innervation of bristles (setae) in Drosophila Manuscripts (1 folder) 1936-1938
Stern, Curt -- Interview - "The normal and abnormal child" Manuscripts (1 item) 1950
Stern, Curt -- Interview - "Race for All" Manuscripts (1 item) 1944
Stern, Curt -- Japan Manuscripts (7 folders) 1956-1957, 1963
Stern, Curt -- Kaiser-Wilhelm Institutes Manuscripts (1 folder) 1920s
Genetics Note (continued)
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Academic Freedom in a totalitarian state" Manuscripts (1 folder) 1936
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "The additional effect of multiple allelomorphs" Manuscripts (7 pages) 1929
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Analysis of testis and duct shape in Drosophila" Manuscripts (1 folder) 1938
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Aspects of gene action in Drosophila" Manuscripts (9 pages) 1948
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Aspects of the position effect of genes" Manuscripts (6 pages) 1945
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Aspects of recent work in genetics" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1942
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Atomic power-eugenic power: who wields them and how is it used?" Manuscripts (4 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "A biologist looks at the world and his profession" Manuscripts (3 pages) 1940
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Biology and Religion" Manuscripts (6 pages) 1937
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Cell Division and Fertilization" (Zellteilung und Befruchtung) Manuscripts (24 pages) 1927
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Chance in evolution" Manuscripts (25 pages) 1947
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "The Child's Heritage" Manuscripts (11 pages) 1957
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Chromosomes of Man" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1968
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, Cold Spring Harbor Symposium Manuscripts (8 pages) 1944
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Diseases of the nervous system in childhood" Manuscripts (6 pages) 1961
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Experiments in developmental genetics" Manuscripts (5 pages) 1969
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Fundamental aspects of medical genetics" Manuscripts (10 pages) 1962
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Fundamentals of Heredity" (Hamburg) Manuscripts (22 pages) 1927
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "General talk on Race" Manuscripts (42 pages) 1948-1949
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genes and differentation" Manuscripts (5 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic aspects in human behavior" Manuscripts (20 pages) 1966
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic aspects of mental defectiveness" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1958
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic aspects of mental disease" Manuscripts (5 pages) 1958
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic aspects of muscular disease" Manuscripts (5 pages) 1964
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic aspects of peptic ulcer and cancer" Manuscripts (9 pages) 1952
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic basis of human behavior" Manuscripts (6 pages) 1966
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic future of man" Manuscripts (9 pages) 1950-1951
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetic selection in man" Manuscripts (10 pages) 1956
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetics and evolution" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1935-1938
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetics in adoption" Manuscripts (16 pages) 1964
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetics in gynecology" Manuscripts (13 pages) 1950
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetics in medical education" Manuscripts (7 pages) 1959
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Genetics of congenital malformations" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1949
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, Hamburg Manuscripts (2 pages) 1927
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Hereditary factors affecting adoption" Manuscripts (18 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Hereditary factors of mental and emotional disturbances" Manuscripts (6 pages) 1951
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Heredity and environment" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1964
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Human genetics counselling" Manuscripts (2 folders) 1954, 1969
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Human genetics: new facts and old problems" Manuscripts (8 pages) 1964
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Human heredity problems" Manuscripts (9 pages) 1968
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Impressions of France and Germany" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1952
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Injuries to hereditary material due to radiation" Manuscripts (2 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Interrelations between general and human genetics" Manuscripts (17 pages) 1967
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Mutation rates" Manuscripts (16 pages) 1955
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "On being a scientist" Manuscripts (9 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "One world: Genes and their action" Manuscripts (2 pages) 1948
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Our changing genetic constitutions" Manuscripts (11 pages) 1967
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, Population problems Manuscripts (2 folders) 1962
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Position effect" Manuscripts (3 folders) 1946, n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Problems of radiobiology with emphasis on radiation genetics" Manuscripts (11 pages) 1951
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Research and Science" Manuscripts (18 pages) 1944
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Science and Religion" Manuscripts (10 pages) 1941
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Sex-determination in plants, animals, and man" Manuscripts (2 pages) 1941
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Social implications of Human Genetics" Manuscripts (6 pages) 1969
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Some General aspects of medical Genetics," "Genetics of selected diseases," "Current concepts in human genetics" Manuscripts (18 pages) 1960, 1962
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Some present-day aspects of Science" Manuscripts (5 pages) 1945
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Some problems of Human Genetics" Manuscripts (2 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "The structure of chromosomes" Manuscripts (11 pages) 1929
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, Student Scientific Conference Manuscripts (4 pages) 1941
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Survey of Human Genetics" Manuscripts (3 folders) 1959-1961
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Use of mosaics in the study of developmental effects of genes" Manuscripts (8 pages) 1966
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, Wells College Manuscripts (3 pages) 1944
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Why do people differ?" Manuscripts (2 pages) 1946
Stern, Curt -- Lecture, "Young scientists, teachers, parents" Manuscripts (4 pages) 1960
Stern, Curt -- Male sterility (notes) Manuscripts (3 pages) 1938
Stern, Curt -- Medawar, Peter Brian Manuscripts (3 pages) 1967
Stern, Curt -- Medical genetics Manuscripts (10 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Mendel and human genetics Manuscripts (8 items) 1965
Stern, Curt -- Model estimations of the frequency of white and near-white segregants in the American Negro Manuscripts (4 folders) 1952-1953
Stern, Curt -- Mosaic diagrams Manuscripts (5 folders) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Mosaics in Drosophila Manuscripts (1 folder) 1934
Stern, Curt -- Mosaics in flies and man Manuscripts (5 pages) 1971
Stern, Curt -- Munich Manuscripts (6 pages) 1972
Stern, Curt -- Naples Manuscripts (1 folder) 1929
Stern, Curt -- Nature-Nurture Manuscripts (3 folders) 1958, n.d.
Stern, Curt -- New data on the problem of Y-linkage of hairy pinnae Manuscripts (8 folders) 1958-1964
Stern, Curt -- New York Times (letters to the Editor) Correspondence (20 items) 1945-1946
Stern, Curt -- A note on the detection of diferential effects of mutagens Manuscripts (11 items) 1956-1957
Stern, Curt -- Notebook on genetics Manuscripts (1 folder) Circa 1949
Stern, Curt -- Notes Manuscripts (1 folder) 1933
Stern, Curt -- Notes and figures on bristle patterns Manuscripts (1 folder) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Notes and sketches, miscellaneous Manuscripts (2 folders) Circa 1923
Stern, Curt -- Notes on genetics of maize Manuscripts (1 folder) Circa 1935
Stern, Curt -- On a case of lethal Ichthyosis in Hiroshima Manuscripts Correspondence (17 items) 1957-1958
Stern, Curt -- On teaching vs. research at the University of California Manuscripts (8 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- On the Occurrence of Translocations and Autosomal non-disjunction in Drosophila Melanogaster Manuscripts (17 items) 1933-1934
Stern, Curt -- The Origin of Genetics (correspondence) Correspondence (16 items) 1965-1967
Stern, Curt -- Personality Questionnaire Manuscripts (1 folder) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Pigmentation mosaicism in intersexes of Drosophila Manuscripts (5 items) 1965-1979
Stern, Curt -- Place of Genetics in Medicine Manuscripts (19 items) 1974
Stern, Curt -- Population Genetics (World Population Conference) Manuscripts (1 folder) 1965
Stern, Curt -- Porcupine Man Manuscripts Correspondence (9 folders) 1948-1958
Stern, Curt -- Principles of Human Genetics Manuscripts (6 boxes) 1942-1983
Stern, Curt -- Problems of Y chromosome inheritance in man Manuscripts Correspondence (2 folders) 1956-1957
Stern, Curt -- Protozoenkurs Sketches (1 folder) 1921-1922
Stern, Curt -- Public Health seminar Manuscripts (9 pages) 1960
Stern, Curt -- Publications in Human Genetics Manuscripts (3 pages) 1973
Stern, Curt -- Radiation Genetics Manuscripts Correspondence (7 folders) 1953-1958
Stern, Curt -- Ratio of monozygotic to dizygotic affected twins and the frequency of affected twins in unselected data Manuscripts (3 folders) 1958
Stern, Curt -- Reflections on Armistice Day, 1940 Manuscripts (1 folder) 1940
Stern, Curt -- Religious questionings Manuscripts (6 pages) 1939
Stern, Curt -- Report on foreign travel Manuscripts (1 folder) 1965
Stern, Curt -- Research grant proposals (N.I.H.). "Mosaicism and developmental genetics in Drosophila" Manuscripts (3 items) 1970
Stern, Curt -- Research grants Manuscripts (2 folders) 1958-1970
Stern, Curt -- Research notes and calculations Manuscripts (4 folders) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Retirement and birthday greetings Manuscripts (1 folder) 1970
Stern, Curt -- Reviews (by Stern) Manuscripts (3 items) 1932-1944
Stern, Curt -- Reviews, "Selection and Eugenics" Correspondence (6 items) 1949
Stern, Curt -- Rhizopoda Manuscripts (1 folder) 1920s
Stern, Curt -- Sabbatical reports Manuscripts (11 items) 1951-1968
Stern, Curt -- Selection, polymorphism Manuscripts (7 pages) 1969
Stern, Curt -- Self-introduction Manuscripts (1 folder) 1962
Stern, Curt -- Sensory physiology of the relation between honeybees and flowers Manuscripts (8 pages) 1942
Stern, Curt -- Sigma Xi lecture tour Notebooks (1 folder) 1952-1953
Stern, Curt -- Somatic recombination within the white locus of Drosophila melanogaster Manuscripts (2 folders) 1968-1969
Stern, Curt -- Some general problems of human inheritance Manuscripts (3 pages) 1939
Stern, Curt -- Speaking engagements (letters, announcements, notes, etc.) Manuscripts (5 folders) 1959-1970
Stern, Curt -- Sturtevant, A. H. Manuscripts (1 folder) Circa 1970
Stern, Curt -- Summary of position effect tests of various translocations Manuscripts (1 folder) 1942
Stern, Curt -- Symposium, "Genetic and Environmental Determinants of Intelligence." Opening remarks of chairman Manuscripts (6 items) 1969
Stern, Curt -- Symposium, "Man and the atomic age" Manuscripts (3 items) 1949
Stern, Curt -- Testis shapes and colors of Drosophila species Manuscripts (3 folders) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Uber Wechselbeziehungen zwischen allgemeiner Genetik und Humangenetik Manuscripts (9 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Unforgettable Kindness Manuscripts (2 pages) 1971
Stern, Curt -- U.S.S.R. Exchange Visit Manuscripts (5 folders) 1963
Stern, Curt -- University of California, Berkeley. Bio-Bibliography Manuscripts (4 folders) 1961-1973
Stern, Curt -- University of California, Berkeley. Faculty Research Lecture Manuscripts (2 folders) 1963-1964
Stern, Curt -- University of California, Berkeley. Zoology 151 address Manuscripts (1 folder) 1970
Stern, Curt -- University of California, Berkeley. Zoology 253 Manuscripts (1 folder) 1968
Stern, Curt -- University of Rochester. "The News about the University of Rochester" Manuscripts (1 letter) 1944
Stern, Curt -- Untersuchungen uber Acanthocystideen Manuscripts (2 folders) 1924
Stern, Curt -- Weinberg, Wilhelm Manuscripts (4 folders) 1956-1973
Stern, Curt -- Whom will our child resemble? Manuscripts (8 pages) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Wing correlation Manuscripts (7 folders) n.d.
Stern, Curt -- Zur Histologie und Regeneration der ungeschlechtlichen Fortpflanzung bei Stenostomum Manuscripts (1 folder) n.d.
Stern, Curt and Belar, Gertrud -- Race crossing in paradise Correspondence (23 items) 1948-1955
Stern, Curt and Bridges, Calvin B. -- The mutants of the extreme left end of the second chromosome of Drosophila melanogaster Manuscripts (4 folders) 1926